PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(chiming music)
（叮铃的音乐声）
- What do I think color is?
- 你问我什么是色彩？
(laughing)
（大笑）
What is color?
什么是色彩？
(gentle cheerful music)
（温柔而愉快的音乐）
- (laughing) I can't answer that question.
摄影指导 灯光师 - （笑）我没法回答这个问题
- (laughing) What is color?
美术指导 - （笑）什么是色彩？
Color is a sensation.
色彩是一种感受
(chiming)
(叮~)
- Color is a very personal thing.
美术指导 - 色彩是非常个人的事情
Color is very subjective.
色彩是非常主观的
It can trigger like a visceral response.
它可以像本能一样被触发
Like if you smell bacon,
如同你闻到了培根
ah, bacon.
啊 这就是培根
You know, it's like if you see certain kinds of colors,
你明白 就好像你看到了 那几种特定的颜色
the same exact feeling.
所感受到的一模一样
- I don't know.
- 我不知道
Ask some smart person here.
还是问问这里的聪明人去吧
Pick-- (laughing)
比如 Pick —— （大笑）
- Color is a term that we use
- 颜色是一种术语
to describe a collection of attributes,
我们用它来描述一类性质
hue and saturation and value,
色相 饱和度 和 明度
that describes how we see things.
这些性质用于描述 我们如何观察事物
Hue is what the actual color is in the rainbow spectrum.
饱和度就是彩虹的光谱中 到底含有什么颜色
Is it more yellow,
它是更偏黄一点呢
or is it more orange?
还是更偏橙一点呢？
Bluer or redder?
蓝一点还是红一点？
Value is how bright something is relative to something else.
明度就是一个物体 相对于另一个物体有多亮
Is it white?
它是白色的么？
Is it black?
还是黑色的呢？
Is it some sort of middle grey?
亦或是某种中灰色？
Saturation is how intense the color is?
饱和度就是颜色有多浓烈
Is it more subdued and grey,
它是更加压抑和灰暗呢
or is it more vibrant, almost fluorescence, you know?
还是更加活泼和艳丽呢？
A fully saturated color is quite eye popping.
你知道 饱和度及其高的颜色 是相当扎眼的
(electricity crackling)
（电器的噼啪声）
Color is everything to artists.
颜色就是艺术家的一切
- It wasn't until I started working at Pixar
- 直到我为皮克斯工作之后
that I think I had to think about color
我才意识到我必须以一种不同的方式
in a different way,
来思考色彩
to apply it to a narrative
以将它用于在讲故事中
and it can mean something.
让它具有某种意义
- On Up, there was a scene where Carl's house
- 在《飞屋环游记》中 有一个场景是卡尔的房子
got burned by Muntz.
被蒙兹烧毁了
It's really one of the lowest points of the film,
它是电影中情绪的一个低谷
and it's this sunrise.
那是一个日出的时候
Normally sunrises are very beautiful.
一般来说 日出是非常美丽的
It's the start of a new day,
它是全新一天的伊始
but for this one, we wanted an angry sunrise.
但是这一个呢 我们希望它是一个恼怒的日出
It was just this beautiful tone of red
我们仅用了一抹如此美丽的红色
that was so dramatic for me.
对我来说这是如此的震撼
I think that was really cool.
我觉得它真的非常的棒
- Because the choice of color is so critical
- 因为对于讲故事而言
to the story telling process,
挑选色彩是至关重要的
it's really important that we understand
对于我们来说
the science of the choosing of those colors.
明白选择色彩的学问 就显得异常重要
The first thing to realize about color
色彩科学家 了解色彩的第一件事情 就是明白
is that color is really made up of light.
色彩是由光组成的
Light comprises different wavelengths of energy,
光线由具有不同波长的能量构成
and when that energy comes through our pupil
当能量穿过我们的瞳孔
onto our retina inside our eye,
到达我们眼中的视网膜上的时候
it becomes nerve impulses, signals,
就转变为了神经冲动 一些信号
and eventually gets processed by the brain.
最终被大脑所处理
So the light is out in the real world.
所以说 光线是存在于真实世界之中的
The color only really exists inside your brain
仅当你察觉到它们的时候
when you perceive it.
色彩才会存在于你的大脑之中
(fireworks popping)
（烟花盛开）
In the rest of this lesson,
在这堂课余下的部分
we're gonna dive more into the science
我们将更加深入科学
and perception of color.
解析色彩
Let's go. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
让我们出发吧 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox